The general environment in which I evolve is
我所处的整体环境是
the engine that can develop me.
能让我发展的动力。
If I take a seed and put it in the fridge, not much will happen.
如果我拿一颗种子放进冰箱，它不会有什么大的变化。
If I put it in the earth, there is light, sun, heat, it can develop.
如果我把它放在泥土里，有光，有阳光，有热量，它就能生长。
If you are in a complicated emotional or other environment, it will
如果你处于一个复杂的情绪或其他环境中，它会
influence.
产生影响。
We know more and more that we can talk about the genetic egg and more and more that we talk about epigenetics.
我们越来越认识到可以谈论遗传卵子，也越来越多地谈论表观遗传。
the force of the environment represents almost 90% of
环境的力量，几乎占了
this power.
这种力量的90%。
The question arises as to what environment your patient lives in.
这就提出了一个问题，你的病人生活在什么样的环境中。
I very often ask the question, where do you live, what do you experience,
我经常问这个问题，你住在哪里，你正在经历什么，
what have you experienced, what are...
你经历过什么，有哪些……
It's all this anamnesis side, but with the idea of, I take a kind of layer
这都是病史的方面，但从概念上讲，我把它看作是
around and I see it.
一层围绕着它，我看到了。
what's happening. We need an environment to develop
发生了什么。我们需要一个环境才能发展，
and secondly
其次是
space. To give space back to the mind, to give space back to the tissue,
空间。给思想留出空间，给组织留出空间，
to give space back
给
to an emotion. Embryology is functional anatomy. And
情感留出空间。胚胎学是功能解剖学。这
what does that mean? It means
意味着什么？它意味着
that it is anatomy that is first in motion. Second, it
首先，解剖学是运动的。其次，它
is anatomy that uses
是利用
the four years.
四个维度。
five dimensions we know, up, down, left, etc. And the fourth dimension
我们知道的五个维度，上、下、左等等。第四个维度
which is the notion of chronos, of time. You will have to be able to look at this
是时间的概念，即“chronos”。你必须能够观察这个
little embryo developing through all its movements and also with sections. This
小胚胎在所有这些运动中发展，而且还有切片。这个
notion is memory. This notion of time is also a notion of memory,
概念就是记忆。时间这个概念也是记忆的概念，
that is to say that you carry time within you. You are a concentration
也就是说，你体内承载着时间。你是一个时间的
of time. And
浓缩。而且
sometimes in the body there are specific areas.
有时身体中存在特定的区域。
which are concentrated areas where the person is blocked.
这些是集中的区域，病人被阻塞了。
A word, a gesture, a look can block a person for their whole life.
一个词，一个手势，一个眼神可以阻碍一个人一生。
And sometimes, this time is found in the tissues.
有时，这种时间会体现在组织中。
And sometimes, you can work, you've already noticed,
有时，你可能会工作，你已经注意到了，
you've done some work, and then all of a sudden,
你做了一项工作，然后突然，
there's an emotional release that happens.
情绪得到了释放。
You have, in fact, released a concentration.
你实际上释放了一个集中。
You put it back in its space.
你把它放回它的空间。
And that, in embryology, is important.
这在胚胎学中很重要。
Because we will be able to find these notions.
因为我们将能够找到这些概念。
If you remember the short film we saw this morning,
如果你还记得我们今天早上看的小电影，
you saw that there were movements where we moved forward,
你会看到有一些向前推进的运动，
and then all of a sudden, movements where it moved back.
然后突然，又有一些后退的运动。
Movements as if there was a wave, like that.
就像波浪一样的运动。
But if you observe that, if there is a movement like that,
但如果你观察一下，如果存在这样的运动，
it means there are points of support.
那一定有支点。
And we will use them as therapeutic tools.
我们将把它们用作治疗工具的支点。
Because the body knows these points of support.
因为身体知道这些支点。
If you give them a good point of support,
如果你给它们一个好的支点，
and it knows where it can develop, it can rebuild itself.
它就知道如何发展，如何重建。
There is the notion that you have time, that there are tissues, that there are fluids,
有一个概念是，你有时间，有组织，有体液，
and everything is expressed in a constellation,
所有这些都以一种星群的形式表达出来，
we say that mind, body, spirit are united.
我们说心、身、灵是合一的。
Mind, body, spirit.
心、身、灵。
So osteopathy is a science based on the art of touch,
因此，骨疗法是一门基于触诊艺术的科学，
which offers true knowledge of the living heart,
它提供了对活生生的心脏的真正认识，
the one that tells the story of anatomy,
讲述了解剖学的故事，
linked to the movement of spirit and mind.
与精神和心智的运动相关联。
One of the goals of osteopathy is to improve exchanges
骨疗法的目标之一是改善交流，
and to have an impact down to the cellular level,
并对细胞层面产生影响，
and even, I think we go further,
甚至，我认为我们走得更远，
that we have impacts even on the genetic level.
我们甚至对基因层面产生影响。
We now prove it by the phenomena of tensegrity
我们现在通过张拉整体现象
and the phenomena of epigenetics,
和表观遗传学现象来证明，
that in fact we have a very profound impact, and we will see how far it goes. The path... My professor, my teacher, had suggested to me, first told me that you must study embryology. He tells me that when you understand embryology well, you will understand what anatomy means. Anatomy will give you physiology. This physiology, you will also have to study its pathos. Its pathophysiology. Then we have psychology, then we have philosophy. Finally, there is spirituality. How conception develops, and where it is how I die. That death...
事实上我们有非常深远的影响，
Its pathophysiology.
它的病理生理学。
Then we have psychology, then we have philosophy.
然后我们有心理学，然后我们有哲学。
Finally, there is spirituality.
最终，还有灵性。
How conception develops, and where it is how I die.
受孕如何发展，以及我如何死亡。
That death...
死亡……
on a developmental level
在发展层面上
is useful.
是有用的。
If there is no cellular death,
如果没有细胞死亡，
I don't like the word death,
我不喜欢“死亡”这个词，
I would always say transformation.
我总是说转化。
It is a continuous transformation.
这是一个持续的转化。
This power that was already established
这种力量早已确立
in the first cell,
在第一个细胞中，
It continues until the end of your life.
它会一直持续到你生命的尽头。
Until your last breath.
直到你咽下最后一口气。
That is, you have this capacity
也就是说，你拥有这种能力
to take the breath of life.
去吸入生命之息。
the breath of life is there
生命之息就在那里
and then I breathe out
然后我呼出我的气息
and I still have
我仍然拥有
the energy to
能量去
take it again
再次吸入
so I can still participate
所以我可以再次参与
and we do that every time, that's where we have the transformation
我们每次都这样做，这就是我们发生转化的地方
I think sometimes people
我认为有时人们
they are stuck in time
他们被时间所困
and that they sometimes come to get
他们有时来是为了获得
information about it
这方面的信息
very often people when they follow
很多人在学习这些课程后，在实践中
these courses, afterwards in practice
这些课程后，在实践中
something happens
会发生一些事情
because
因为
we go into something where no mind can intervene,
我们进入了一个没有心智可以干预的领域，
but there is a modification that happens inside.
但内在会发生改变。
Because we will see the development of the perfect embryo, as they say.
因为我们将看到完美的胚胎发育，正如我们所说。
We will be in the blueprint, which keeps its median line, which has no deviation.
我们将处于蓝图中，它保持其中线，没有偏差。
This is my birth, this is the space of my conception.
这是我的诞生，是我受孕的空间。
And sometimes you have the median line here, you are in the right axis.
有时你的中线在这里，你在正确的轴线上。
Sometimes you can already deviate at your conception.
有时你可能在受孕时就已经偏离了。
be deviated at your birth, you can be deviated by a trauma.
出生时偏离，你可能因创伤而偏离。
And we must recognize
我们必须认识到
these points.
这些点。
Non-recognition
不认识到
develops all
会发展出所有
compensatory activities.
代偿性活动。
So I must, at some point,
所以我在某个时刻，
by the quality of my presence,
通过我临在的品质，
by the quality of touch,
通过触诊的品质，
by what the tissue will inform you,
通过组织会告诉你的信息，
be able to recognize
能够识别
these spaces.
这些空间。
And there, he can have
在那里，它可能会有
a...
一个...
a trust
一个矫正的推力
of correction
矫正的推力
you just have to be present
你只需要在场
for the touch
去触碰它
because there is no will
因为没有意志
that's what's really important
这才是真正重要的
the body has a capacity for self-regulation
身体具有自我调节的能力
of self-regulation
自我调节
and to maintain its health
并保持其健康
and so this notion of strength
所以这种力量的概念
of nature
自然的
is to reconnect with that
就是重新连接到它
we see very well
我们很清楚地看到
if now there is no more human impact
如果现在没有人为影响，
nature quickly reclaims its rights and we have been somewhat cut off from
大自然会很快完全恢复其权利，而我们有点与此脱节。在这样的发展中，大自然就在那里。我们干预得越少，就越好。
that. As long as this development is there, nature is there. The less we intervene, the better
越好。另一个
it is. Another
原则是结构与功能互惠的概念，
principle is the notion of reciprocity of structure and function and
以及所有
all of
这些原则是，身体必须考虑到所有这些，
these principles is that the body, you have to take all of this into account and
因此要意识到
therefore become aware
我可以使用它。
that I can use that.
这真的很实用。
It's really practical.
它有这种力量。
That it has this power.
那它要求什么呢？
And what does it ask for?
它只是要求被调整。
It's simply that it be adjusted.
有些医生专门治疗小手指。
There are doctors who specialize in little fingers.
这很棒。
It's great.
同时，他们不仅仅看到下肢，例如，或者上肢，
At the same time, they don't see that the lower limb, for example, or upper,
它是一个腹膜囊的扩张。
is an expansion of a peritoneal sac.
原子会形成分子。
Atoms will form molecules.
分子会形成细胞。
Molecules will form cells.
细胞会形成组织。
Cells form tissues.
组织会形成器官。
Tissues form organs.
所以，最终，我就是一堆
So, ultimately, I am a kind of package
在你们面前移动的原子。
And before the atom, there is also this whole notion of energy.
在原子之前，还有能量的整个概念。
So, ultimately, what we perceive is a set of energies.
所以，最终，我们感知到的是一个能量的集合。
It's a package of energy that sometimes needs to be a bit structural.
它是一个能量包，有时需要一些结构。
Which thinks, moreover.
它还会思考。
Onto, Genesis.
个体发生。
Onto, that means being.
个体发生，意思是存在。
And Genesis, that means formation.
发生，意思是形成。
Ontogenesis is the formation of a being.
个体发生，是一个存在的形成。
We will study the ontogenesis of man.
我们将研究人类的个体发生。
And especially in its morphogenesis.
尤其是在其形态发生学中。
So in its morph, in its form, and
所以，在其形态中，在其形式中，以及
the formation of this form.
这种形式的形成。
An individual.
一个个体。
Phylogenesis, that covers the history of the development of all species.
系统发生学，它涵盖了所有物种发展史。
through time. We will study human ontogenesis. We will especially
随着时间的推移。我们将研究人类的个体发生。我们将主要
look for the form
研究形式
and this power of human development and see the impacts we can have
以及人类发展的这种力量，并观察我们可能产生的影响
in practice.
在实践层面。